# Harsh Pathania 1. Harsh Pathania 1. Harsh Pathania 1. Linkedin:in/hp959/♠ github.com/evolutionharsh

# **Profile**

Experienced Software Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the software industry with near about +5 years of experience. Possess a strong understanding of business requirements with a Master's degree specializing in Software Engineering from the University of Illinois.

#### Education

University of Illinois at Springfield, IL, USA

Aug'15-Dec'16

Master in Science, Computer Science, GPA: 3.62/4.0 Lovely Professional University, Punjab, India

2007-2011

Bachelor in Science, Computer Science, GPA: 3.3/4.0

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: CSharp, JavaScript, Java, Typescript

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, NodeJS, Angular Js (8,10), MVC4.0, ASP. NET 4.5/4.7, RestAPI, Azure Cloud

**Database:** MSSQL(2012,2016,2018),Oracle 11g/12c

Tools and Frameworks: Visual Studio(2019/2022), VSCode, Eclipse, GitHub, Jenkins

# **Professional Experience**

### Sr Software Engineer, KForce Inc

Boston, MA 06/2023 - Present

Client-Microsoft

- Work on Microsoft Partner Connect (MPC) portal performed migration of +15 microservices from azure function apps to webapps.
- Wrote backend code in CSharp with Razor View Engine, Entity Framework to create Model classes in Visual Studio 2022.
- Designed and implemented a cloud-based solution using Azure services such as App Services, Functions and Logic Apps, resulting in increase in application performance reduction in operational costs.

#### Sr Software Engineer, American Express

Boston, MA *08/2021 - 05/2023* 

- Worked on MVC 4.0 web application wrote code in CSharp.Implemented REST APIs with azure service fabric stateless Microservices using .NET Core.
- Designed the front-end screens and developed responsive Web Pages using Bootstrap, HTML5, Angular 10. Worked on Angular JS of Scopes, Models, Directives, Filters, Services, Dependency Injection, Routing and Prototyping.
- Architect and implement REST API interfaces using Javascript and Node.Js.Extensively used Promises and Event emitter in Node.Js to avoid callback.

## Sr Software Engineer, MASSDOT

Boston, MA 04/2019 - 07/2021

- Wrote backend code in Csharp for legacy web application with RazorViewPages in VS2019. The frontend developed in Angular 10,HTML5, CSS3.
- Worked with Product Owners, business stakeholders to understand the requirement and ship the product as per requirement.
- Created typescript reusable components and services to consume REST API's using component architecture provided by Angular Js.

#### **Sr Software Engineer** Caterpillar Inc

Peoria, IL 03/2017 - 12/2018

- Developed web application using .NET4.5,MVC 4.0,RazorViews,CSharp,Javascript,Angular8,HTML5, CSS3.
- Wrote Unix shell scripts to process the files like extracting data from files.Created PL/SQL scripts for data manipulation and validation.
- Deployement of web services using CSharp and exposed them through SOAP and HTTP.

#### **Software Engineer** *Mphasis Ltd*

**Bangalore, India** 01/2014 - 2/2015

- Implemented Server and Client side validations using ASP. NET (4.5) validation controls and ExpressJs.
- Involved in the development of the UI using HTML5, CSS3, Angular Js in compliance to WCAG 2.0 standards.
- Involved in Scrum meetings worked in agile methodology created documentation prepared used cases, identify classes objects developed class diagrams as part of documentation.

# Certifications

- Micrsoft Azure serverless certified App Developer.
- Scale Certified SAFe 4 Practitioner.
- The Art Science of Product Management.
- The Business of Product Management.